mnsure.org 2015-06-12

# Terms and Conditions

## Terms of Use

The MNsure system is the property of the State of Minnesota and is subject to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act.

In order to purchase insurance through the MNsure system, an applicant will have to create an online account. This account access is granted subject to compliance with law and the terms and conditions for use. Users are responsible for maintaining confidentiality of their personal account information. By using the MNsure system, applicants certify that the information provided is true and accurate. MNsure applicants and account holders have a duty to ensure the accuracy, relevance, timeliness, and completeness of personally identifiable information, as is reasonably necessary, to assure fairness in making determinations about an individual. MNsure applicants and account holders may not knowingly or willingly conceal, remove, mutilate, obliterate, falsify, or destroy information.

Providing false information or using information obtained through the MNsure system for unauthorized purposes is a violation of law and may subject you to criminal and/or civil penalties. Fraud, waste, abuse, and any attempt to breach the security of the system are strictly prohibited, and any suspected misuse, fraud, waste, or abuse should be reported to [mnsurecompliancehotline@mnsure.org](mailto:mnsurecompliancehotline@mnsure.org "email compliance").

MNsure Applicants or individuals who provide and view information on behalf of household members, dependents, employees or others verify that they have the permission of the individual data subject, or are the legal guardian, or are otherwise authorized to access and submit the information, and must agree to safeguard it. Individuals who view or submit information on behalf of another individual also agree to only use personally identifiable information for the purpose of completing the proper application or as otherwise allowed by state or federal law and to safeguard the data from unauthorized access, use, modification, destruction, theft, or disclosure.

### © copyright notice

The webpage(s) you just visited are protected by the copyright laws of the United States of America. Pursuant to Title 17 of the United States Code, the author of original visually perceivable work validly provides notice of a copyright by placing the "AF," "©," or the word "Copyright" in a conspicuous location followed by the first year of publication and text identifying the name of the owner of the copyright.

The author of the web site you just visited has clearly published notice of the copyright and the intention to protect the rights associated therewith. Unless otherwise indicated, a link from your web site to the copyrighted web page(s) is NOT an infringement upon the copyright.

The fair use of a copyrighted work for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching (including multiple copies for classroom use), scholarship, or research, is not an infringement of copyright. Any other use is a violation of the laws of the United States of America.

## Rules of Behavior for MNsure Employees and Contractors

The MNsure system is the property of the State of Minnesota and is subject to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act. By using this system, you are representing yourself as an authorized user, and as such, you agree to use the system for authorized purposes only and in compliance with state and federal law. Users of the system who have the ability to see the personal information of participants, including state employees, contractors, community assistance partners, and other system users, must adhere to rules of behavior for protection of private participant information. These rules are consistent with and in addition to state and federal laws and the privacy and security policies and procedures for MNsure, including the Minnesota Department of Human Services (DHS) Information and Technology Policies and Procedures, and the Appropriate Use of Electronic Communication and Technology Policy (applicable only to state employee users). Non-compliance with the rules and associated security policies may be cause for disciplinary actions including suspension and/or termination of access privileges, employment consequences, and/or civil and criminal legal action. 

  * 1\. System Use
  * 2\. Unauthorized Access Prohibited
  * 3\. Monitoring
  * 4\. Users Duty
  * 5\. Authorized Purposes Only
  * 6\. Security Obligations
  * 7\. Incident Reporting
  * 8\. Disclosures
  * 9\. Data Integrity

## Privacy Policy

MNsure has taken a number of steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information that is maintained in agency computer systems. These measures are designed and intended to ensure the integrity of information that is transmitted, to block unknown or unauthorized access, and to provide reasonable protection of private information within the system.

When you visit the MNsure public website and browse or download information, including browsing and comparing insurance plans on the anonymous shopping feature, we automatically collect and store information about your visit, including the Internet Protocol (IP) address and domain name used, the type of browser and operating system used, the date and time you visited this site, the pages or services you accessed, and the website you visited prior to coming to this website. This information is not readily identifiable to an individual and is used to analyze web traffic and improve our web service.

We use “cookies” to customize your browsing experience with the MNsure public website. A cookie contains unique tracking information for lists of pages you have visited and the date when you last looked at a specific page, to identify your session, distinguishing among visitors. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer. These session cookies are deleted at the conclusion of your internet browsing session.

This website contains links to other sites, and when you link to another site, you are no longer on the MNsure website and subject to this Privacy Policy. The State of Minnesota, MNsure or any agents, officers, or employees do not warrant the accuracy or reliability of the linked site nor endorse any content, products or services from the linked site. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from a linked site does so at his or her own risk.

## Privacy Warnings

Privacy Warnings are designed to provide you with information about how your private data may be used and shared in proximity to when that data is being collected.
